[Music]
I've been using Playright MCP for the
past few days to get cursor self-improve
the UI and application and become my
automated QA assistant that can run
sophisticated testings by itself. So
today I want to show you what my
workflow is and how can you adopt it for
your own project. Nowadays you normally
hear playright for those browser agent
but initially it is introduced to do
endtoend testing for web applications.
It can simulate browser interaction like
text input, mouse click, scrolling the
page and extract data so that we can
actually write some scripts to simulate
how a real user going to interact with
the website. For example, I might want
to build a task for the normal sign up
and check out flow for the AI builder
club where user should be able to click
a button, type in the email address,
joining, receive the code and log to the
platform. To do that, I can just write a
test script with playright where it can
open the browser, go to the website URL,
click on the sign up button, type in the
email address and clicking on the
button. In the end, we can validate if
the user actually receive the code to
login. And this test can be run every
time before I try to push some change to
the production code. So you can capture
arrow before it goes to production. And
this all sounds great. But building test
is not exactly fun part of building
software. To build those kind of testing
script, you normally need to build very
specific letters to be able to identify
UI elements by using CSS or XP pass.
Even though there are tools like cogen
which is feature from playright that
allow you to do a command line like this
which will open up the browser as well
as a recorder on the right side so that
you can just click through the UI flow
like how a real user going to do and on
the right side it will automatically
capture and generating the testing code
for you based on action you taken but
still it is quite a manual process and
if you change the elements or layout of
the web location this test going to
break and you need to update your test
again but playright released its own MC
CP it basically give cursor agent access
to the browser and that means a few
things. One is that instead of you
defining very static test yourself. You
can get cursor to use playrite to run
the browser and become your QA tester.
On the other side because cursor now has
access to the web browser. It can see
what is going on on the web page
identify any UI bugs or flaw in the flow
and selfiterate until the application
works exactly like what expected. And
this to me is such a gamecher. It open
up so much possibilities. You can even
turn cursor into a general web scripper
where you can open the browser, take a
snapshot of content available on the
page and do complex interaction with web
page to get specific information that
you want. So today I'm going to tell you
what are different ways you can utilize
playrite mcp to do automated testing and
get cursor to self fixing the issue. But
before we dive into that, I know many of
you are building AI applications or
integrating AI into your own business.
And choosing the right model, prompting
techniques is often a challenging task
since there's so many new stuff every
month. That's why I want to introduce
you to this free playbook from Mind
Stream. It breaks down everything from
which AI model is best for which task to
advanced prompting frameworks like GRWC
that can boost your results up to 55%. A
feature compare top models like GB4.5,
cloud 3.7, work 3 plus practical tips on
using specialized model for business
tasks like how cloud 3.7 sonnet is best
for sortful analysis across long
documents while mix large focus on mass
problems. So no more guessing work about
which model fits your specific task
best. And what I love the most is there
are advanced prompting frameworks and
power techniques for better prompts.
Those are exact strategies that I use
when working with AI to create better
code and automate testing workflows.
Those frameworks and techniques
transform mediocre outputs into
exceptional ones and can be applied for
scenario like prompting turser to use
playright MCP to do automated testing
better and you can download this
playbook for free. I have put a link in
the description below so you can click
and check out. And now let's get back to
how you can use playright MCP. Firstly,
let's set up the playright MCP. So to
use playright MCP, you actually can't
use the latest version for now because
the latest version somehow has some
issues. I will go to the mpm package.
The last version that I found quite
stable is this
0.0.2. So if you go to cursor at mcp
this is setup I will have. So playright
and run mpx at
playright/mcp at
0.0.2. And there are also some
additional configurations I have here.
One is this d-config to a specific
configuration file that I created here.
So playright allow you to define
configuration file that including all
the different settings you have like
which type of browser it should be using
what are device it should simulate the
user profile and whether should be using
vision stuff like that. I specifically
use this because I have a few different
settings that I often use to making sure
it can go through certain website that
has anti-bot setup like those special
arguments the user agent initial
scripts. If you're interested you can
join the AI builder club. I have
specific content that dive deep into how
to handle antibboard setup as well as
website that require login and
authentications. I have put a link in
the description below for you to join.
So for this specific case, I will create
this config file and do d-config and
point to this specific file. I also do
d-vision to turn on the vision ability
so that cursor can actually see what's
going on the web page. And I will
actually create two different MCP
servers, one with vision, one without
vision. That's because vision model is
particularly good at certain scenario
like when you wanted to view what's
going on the page and iterate the UI but
it is less good at allocated specific
position to click or UI elements to
interact with and that is quite
essential when you want playright to do
the testing. So I will have another MCP
called playright test which don't have
the vision model. And now when I go back
to MCP I can see there are two MCPS
added at any given time I will just turn
on one of them and firstly I will use
the one with vision model to show you
how can you use playright to run the
application look at UI and self iterate
to improve the interface. So here we
have a basic to-do app the UI individual
component looks actually pretty good but
altogether just something looks a bit
off. This is a very common scenario when
you do AI coding. It's that 20 or 30%
missing that makes the UI just not as
sleek. So I'm going to give prompt.
Please use playright MCP to view the UI.
Identify area to improve for UI and
iterate it until it looks perfect. And
here I just put a small text here. Make
sure the width of browser in MCP to be
700 pixel so it's easier for me to just
show you guys side by side. So it will
open the browser and resize to be
smaller one as you can see here. Then it
will do this browser screen capture to
look at what's on the UI here. then
start doing the iterations. The first
thing you would do is try to refine the
car spacing and input field. So spacing
does look a little bit better especially
around this part of UI. So it change to
something like this which does actually
looks better. And the last bit is that
the task item background and spacing
could be adjusted for even more notion
style and we could improve alignment.
Cool. So after a few rounds of iteration
and feedback, the UI is a lot more clean
now. much better than what we have
before. And this is all thanks to
Playright MCP ability to look at a
screenshots directly and make more
accurate iterations. Next, let's talk
about how to use Playright MCP to do
automated UI testing. Let's assume I
just turn this to-do app into a fully
functional application that requires
some login and once people log in, they
can start adding to-do tasks like
prepare the scripts. Assume the testing
we want to do is we want to making sure
the login authentication works and we
also want to test whether users can add
task successfully and meanwhile I also
add this cursor rules. So our give
prompt we have a simple to-do app set up
in NexJS. Now let's test application
using the playright MCP. Firstly let's
test if you can login successfully and
then test if users can successfully add
to-dos and mark things as completed. So
you can see it first they try to inject
the rules that we just written here
which is two specific things one is that
making sure you always resize screen to
this way so it's easier for us to view
and also the select tab index start from
one instead of zero so this is one kind
of problem I often see they have for
some reason it keep failing to focus on
the specific input and I think this is
because we are using the vision which is
great for UI iterations but not as great
for doing the tests. I'm going to
disable the original one but use a
playright test instead. And just to
making sure I also restart the cursor
and it successfully put in the email and
password sign in and then start testing
adding the tasks change the label. Click
add and the task has been added and I
also check if the show complete function
works as well. Great. This you can see
it's pretty sophisticated. It did pretty
complex test flow. What's really really
cool is that obviously this test is
really smart but it does consume token
and credits every time because it is
going through live learning model to
make it reusable every time. I think
there are two approaches. One is that
since this prompt already works you can
create a folder called tests and then
just save all those test prompts and
every time it just goes through this
flow to do the tests as a AI agent but
obviously the downside of that is that
it does cost money. So what you can also
do is that give it a prompt after it
successfully complete the flow that you
expected and then say now let's create a
reusable playright UI test based on the
flow above so I can run as automated
test every time. So it will install
playright test set up the playright
configuration which will store the
information about which URL to go what's
the browser it should be using for
testing and then it create a UI test
that we can use and now you can see it
write a bunch of different tests for
testing logging and adding tasks
complete tasks and then it tried to run
the test itself which it passed but
three of them failed I can just prompt
it to continue which will reflect what
are the arrows in the test and update
the test here. Now all the tests has
been written for your to-do app and it
also have a raid me that including how
to run those tests. It even create a
GitHub action that if you push this
ripple to GitHub every time when you
want to merge some new change to your
GitHub repo, it will has to go through
those tests and only after those tests
are passed then you will be able to push
to production which will makes whole
process fairly automated and all you
need to do is really just open the
terminal. If you want to test manually,
all you need to do just run this mpm run
test end to end and it'll just
automatically run through all those task
and tell you if they pass or not. So
this is how you can use playr MCP to do
more AIdriven tests either using large
range model agent or let articulate the
specific testing scripts that you can
use for any new changes that you are
trying to push in production. If you're
interested, you can join the AI build
club where I have step-by-step setup
guide for everything I show in this
video. a more in-depth course of how to
best set up to avoid antibbot as well as
website that require login and
authentications alongside with many
other in-depth content from either me or
other industry experts I talked to
around AI coding and building large
language model applications in
production. And we also provide premium
tool that will really bootstrap your AI
coding process like a platform that
convert your ideas into a product
requirement dot that can steer AI coding
agent better as well as launch kit that
already set up the authentication
superbase and stripe. But most
importantly, you'll be joining a
community of top AI builders who are
launching and building their own AI
startups who might already have the
answer to the challenge that you are
facing today. I have put the link in the
description below for you to join. I
hope you enjoyed this video. Thank you
and I see you next